<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<description>Daily top news from newsminimalist.com. Read by 7000 minimalists.</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
<atom:link href="https://rss.beehiiv.com/feeds/4aF2pGVAEN.xml" rel="self"/>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 15:30:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 15:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-24T15:22:05Z</atom:published>
<atom:updated>2023-06-24T15:30:07Z</atom:updated>
<category>News</category>
<category>Society</category>
<category>World</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2023, News Minimalist daily</copyright>
<image>
<url>https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/publication/logo/d0318cb6-0493-4e34-b055-76456e6c0f76/u1f422_u1f30d.png</url>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
</image>
<docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>beehiiv</generator>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>support@beehiiv.com (Beehiiv Support)</webMaster>
<item>
<title>6 月 24 日星期六——3 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>乌克兰核电站即将遭受袭击、全球脊髓灰质炎疫苗分发、俄罗斯爆发武装叛乱</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-june-24-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-june-24-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 15:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-24T15:22:05Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 876 top news stories and gave 5 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/301d3fe6-9e9d-4f59-a5f3-86af2e5ae6ca/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Ukrainian intelligence warns of potential Russian attack on nuclear plant — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newstatesman.com/world/europe/ukraine/2023/06/russia-plan-blow-up-zaporizhzhia-nuclear-plant-drafted-approved" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New Statesman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;In an interview, Kyrylo Budanov, leader of Ukraine&amp;#39;s military intelligence organization, warned that Russia has prepared for an attack on the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant in Ukraine. Russian forces have allegedly mined the cooling pond of the plant and moved explosive-laden vehicles close to four of the power units, potentially causing a nuclear accident. According to Budanov, such an attack could either occur if Russian forces are driven away from a strategic location, creating a zone of destruction, or as a preemptive measure to stop Ukraine&amp;#39;s offensive. The decision to attack has reportedly been drafted and approved, and only awaits the order to proceed. Budanov&amp;#39;s warnings follow a similar announcement by Ukraine&amp;#39;s President Volodymyr Zelensky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] The Vaccine Alliance&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;board to vote on new inactivated polio vaccine for global distribution — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.statnews.com/2023/06/23/polio-eradication-six-in-one-vaccine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;STAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, is likely to approve a new vaccine that combines different vaccines, including one for polio. This six-in-one vaccine, called hexavalent, would protect children from polioviruses and other diseases. By offering this combined vaccine, Gavi aims to ensure that countries continue vaccinating against polio even after it&amp;#39;s eradicated. The new vaccine is expected to be available next year and would strengthen the polio eradication efforts. Although it may cost more, it would require fewer doses and provide better health outcomes. The goal is to improve immunity against polio and move closer to its complete eradication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;This article didn’t get a score over 7, but we decided to make an exception and include it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[6.7] Owner of Wagner PMC calls for armed rebellion in Russia — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/russia-accuses-mercenary-boss-of-mutiny-after-he-says-moscow-killed-2-000-of-his-men-1.6453680" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;CTV News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The owner of the Wagner private military contractor, Yevgeny Prigozhin, has called for an armed rebellion in Russia, directly challenging the Kremlin. He accused Russia&amp;#39;s defense minister of incompetence and called for his ousting. The security services swiftly responded by issuing an arrest warrant for Prigozhin. The Kremlin has taken the threat seriously, increasing security measures in Moscow and Rostov-on-Don, the headquarters for the southern region&amp;#39;s military operations in Ukraine. While the outcome remains uncertain, Prigozhin claimed that his forces had crossed into Russia from Ukraine and reached Rostov without resistance. He vowed to eliminate anyone who obstructed their path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=66ec378a-4d85-4623-85db-49f69e06b15a&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 23 日星期五——5 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>全球糖尿病激增、奥运会拳击丑闻、电动汽车电池投资、美印联盟加强以及乳腺癌疫苗试验前景光明</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-june-23-5-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-june-23-5-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 14:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-23T14:50:55Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 852 top news stories and gave 6 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/486d75be-3d14-422f-9d21-2a8b63d40ece/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[8.0] Diabetes cases worldwide projected to double by 2050, driven by obesity and demographic shifts — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.statnews.com/2023/06/22/global-diabetes-surpass-billion-lancet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;STAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The number of people with diabetes worldwide is set to more than double to 1.3 billion by 2050, according to a new study published in the Lancet. The rise will be driven by type 2 diabetes, which made up 96% of diabetes cases worldwide in 2021, and type 2 diabetes cases will in large part be driven by obesity, a primary risk factor for the disease. Diabetes has traditionally been thought of as a disease that occurs in high-income countries, but it’s increasingly affecting low- and middle-income countries as well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] International Olympic Committee cuts ties with International Boxing Association amid bribery and match-fixing allegations — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/olympics/2023/06/22/ioc-cuts-ties-with-iba/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The International Olympic Committee (IOC) has cut ties with the International Boxing Association (IBA) for the first time in its 128-year history, following allegations of bribery and match fixing at the 2016 Rio Olympics. The IOC’s executive board recommended this month that the organisation move on from the IBA, leaving boxing without an official governing body. However, the decision opens a path for World Boxing, the breakaway federation formed in April by the US, UK, the Netherlands and other countries, to receive IOC recognition and oversee boxing at the Olympics. The IOC has repeatedly warned the IBA that the sport was in danger of being dropped altogether unless it enacted reforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] US Department of Energy to lend $9.2bn for electric vehicle battery factories — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/f473adc6-a187-4297-b4fe-1c22c613f1b1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The US Department of Energy&amp;#39;s Loan Programs Office plans to lend a record $9.2bn to Ford and South Korea&amp;#39;s SK On for the construction of three electric vehicle battery factories in Kentucky and Tennessee. The loan is part of a clean energy investment push by the federal government to develop domestic supply chains and reduce reliance on China. The factories will enable more than 120 GWh of US battery production annually, displacing more than 455 million gallons of petrol a year. The loan is the largest investment in the two-decade history of the Loan Programs Office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] US President Joe Biden hosts Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi for state visit to strengthen ties — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2023/06/22/us/modi-biden-visit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;US President Joe Biden welcomed Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi to the White House for a state visit aimed at strengthening ties between the two countries. The visit is part of Biden&amp;#39;s efforts to build alliances against Russia and China. The two leaders are expected to announce initiatives to advance cooperation on telecommunications, semiconductors, artificial intelligence, and other areas. They will also sign the Artemis Accords, a set of principles governing peaceful exploration of the moon, Mars, and other celestial bodies, and announce a joint mission to the International Space Station in 2024. The visit comes amid concerns about India&amp;#39;s backsliding on democracy and human rights issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Clinical trials underway for breast cancer vaccine with potential to prevent disease — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/opinion/2023/06/23/commentary/world-commentary/breast-cancer-vaccines/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Japan Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Several clinical trials have been conducted in the last six months to develop a breast cancer vaccine that could prevent the disease from occurring. The vaccine would teach the immune system to fight breast cancer before it becomes a problem, potentially reducing the number of women diagnosed with the disease and eliminating the need for preventive mastectomies for women with a family history of breast cancer. While the studies are still in the early stages, the development of multiple breast cancer vaccine trials is a promising sign of progress in using the immune system to prevent cancer. Breast cancer is the most common form of cancer among women in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=95a6219f-b91c-44a0-9b64-bff31d477695&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 22 日星期四——4 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>新兴市场实力崛起、华尔街对美联储通胀立场、供应链重塑以及巴黎峰会雄心勃勃的金融改革做出反应</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-june-22-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-june-22-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 14:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-22T14:27:45Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 867 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/a5aa235f-8453-47a3-b750-8ab70fd55801/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[8.1] Emerging markets to account for over 50% of global economic output by 2050 — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.manilatimes.net/2023/06/22/business/top-business/ph-among-top-20-economies-by-2050/1897201" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Manila Times&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;According to a prediction by Fitch Group unit, BMI Country Risk &amp;amp; Industry Research, by 2050, emerging markets (EMs) are expected to account for more than half of the global economic output. China is anticipated to become the world&amp;#39;s largest economy, and the Philippines is projected to make it to the top 20 economies list, securing the 18th spot. This predicted change is owing to China&amp;#39;s fervent growth. BMI also predicts that China&amp;#39;s share in global financial output will increase from 17.3% in 2023 to 24.3% in 2050. Besides, countries like Bangladesh, Indonesia, Vietnam, and the Philippines, with booming populations and swiftly developing sectors like manufacturing, are expected to enhance their share in global GDP by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Wall Street indexes fall as Federal Reserve Chair remains firm on 2% inflation target — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-muted-ahead-powells-congressional-testimony-2023-06-21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Wall Street&amp;#39;s main indexes, including the Nasdaq, S&amp;amp;P 500, and Dow, fell on Wednesday as Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell remained firm in bringing inflation back to the 2% target, spurring worries of more monetary tightening. All S&amp;amp;P 500 sub-sectors fell, with the rate-sensitive real estate sector leading the declines. Megacap companies struggled to gain as yields on the 2-year treasury notes, which move in line with interest rate expectations, rose marginally after Powell&amp;#39;s comments. Crypto firms, including Coinbase, Riot Platforms, Marathon Digital, and Bit Digital, rose between 2.6% and 9%, tracking an uptick in Bitcoin prices, which hit the highest level in six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Global supply chains restructuring due to geopolitical tensions and pandemic lessons — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.smh.com.au/business/the-economy/it-s-time-to-hasten-slowly-as-rate-cycle-nears-its-end-20230622-p5diig.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Sydney Morning Herald&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;(this is an opinion article, but I decided to keep it for consistency)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Global supply chains are changing due to tensions between the US and China, the war in Ukraine, and the lessons learned from the pandemic. The restructuring of these supply chains, the push for re-shoring and friend-shoring of strategic production, will raise costs and have a continuing impact on inflation rates. The Fed and other major central banks are pushing against a tide that contains some unconventional factors, and this is not a conventional inflation cycle because it reflects structural changes occurring within the global economy that will play out over years, if not decades. The central banks&amp;#39; targets are arbitrary, and there&amp;#39;s no science to them, just a gut feel that 2 per cent is about right based on the central banks&amp;#39; historical experiences. It makes sense for the Fed and other central banks to pause while waiting for more data, given how volatile, complex, and largely unprecedented today&amp;#39;s global economic and geopolitical circumstances are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Paris summit aims to develop new global financial system to combat poverty and climate change — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.france24.com/en/environment/20230621-paris-summit-aims-to-overhaul-global-financial-system-for-more-climate-solidarity-with-south" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;FRANCE 24 English&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron is hosting a summit in Paris on 22-23 June to develop a new global financial system to help vulnerable countries combat poverty and climate change. The summit will bring together around 50 heads of state, representatives from international institutions and civil society. The aim is to build a new contract between the global North and South, and to lay the foundations for an overhaul of the entire global financial system by adapting the post-war Bretton Woods institutions – the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank – to today&amp;#39;s challenges. The financial needs of the Global South are colossal, with estimates ranging from $1tn to $27tn needed to fight poverty, inequality and climate change in developing countries between now and 2030.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=ed64b945-8cae-4dd8-9e28-689790437d46&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 21 日星期三——2 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>欧盟生态系统恢复法，美国宇航局二氧化碳可视化</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-june-21-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-june-21-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 14:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-21T14:31:45Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 832 top news stories and gave 3 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/c5728107-b843-4745-ad1e-83bb9c7fbef1/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] EU member states agree on draft law to restore ecosystems by 2030 and 2050 — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.thejournal.ie/eu-nature-restoration-law-6098721-Jun2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;TheJournal.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The 27 member states of the European Union have agreed on a draft law that would require them to restore at least 20% of the EU’s land and 20% of the EU’s seas by 2030, as well as similar measures for all damaged ecosystems including forests in need of restoration by 2050. The proposal is aligned with the historic biodiversity agreement signed last year. Despite this agreement, the law has encountered resistance from some member states. Austria, Belgium, the Netherlands, Poland, and Sweden have refused to support the law, raising concerns over various factors including impacts on the forestry industry and considerations for densely populated or intensive farming regions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] NASA visualizations show carbon dioxide emissions and sources across the planet — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.iflscience.com/see-where-all-the-carbon-dioxide-comes-from-in-incredible-nasa-visualization-69457" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;IFLScience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;NASA&amp;#39;s Scientific Visualization Studio has released three videos that show the amount of carbon dioxide added to the atmosphere each year, its sources, and where it comes from on the planet. The visualizations are based on data from NASA&amp;#39;s Orbiting Carbon Observatory, 2 (OCO-2), which provides the most complete dataset of atmospheric carbon dioxide concentration across the planet. The videos show that fossil fuel burning by industrialized countries plays a significant role in the amount of greenhouse gases released into the air. The natural world can only absorb about half of the carbon dioxide produced annually, and the rest is spread around the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=e57204e5-d05e-4c4d-adfe-81b36af7bce3&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 20 日星期二 — 1 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>具有里程碑意义的海洋保护公海条约</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-june-20-1-significant-news-story</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-june-20-1-significant-news-story</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 15:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-20T15:51:51Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1094 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/00c583e0-81d2-41f0-9a63-1da916b2e36e/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] UN adopts first treaty to protect high seas and preserve marine biodiversity — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-06-20/un-adopts-world-s-first-treaty-to-protect-high-seas-biodiversity/102498694" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;ABC News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The United Nations has adopted the world&amp;#39;s first treaty on the protection of the high seas and the conservation of marine biodiversity in international waters after more than 15 years of discussions and five rounds of negotiations led by the UN. A legally binding agreement will regulate the sharing of benefits derived from marine genetic resources beyond national jurisdiction, establish protected areas on the high seas and establish a framework for assessing environmental damage. The agreement will be open for signature in New York for two years, starting on September 20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=f494af5b-73ed-4af1-981b-06fd6ac65786&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 19 日星期一——3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>俄罗斯非军事化主张被揭穿、乌克兰反攻成功、奥地利挫败维也纳阅兵式恐怖袭击</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-june-19-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-june-19-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 14:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-19T14:40:03Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read &lt;span style="color:rgb(51, 65, 85);"&gt;1070&lt;/span&gt; top news stories and gave 3 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/acff92fa-608a-4074-a69e-12236b469cbc/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] Russia claims Ukraine demilitarized despite evidence to the contrary — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsweek.com/kremlin-bizarrely-claims-goal-demilitarizing-ukraine-largely-completed-1807517" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Newsweek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Russian officials claimed on Saturday that Ukraine had been demilitarized, in line with Moscow&amp;#39;s invasion of the country, despite evidence to the contrary. The invasion began in February 2022, with Russia citing a number of justifications that were quickly scrutinized as dubious by experts. One of the claims made frequently by Russia has been about the need to demilitarize Ukraine. However, Ukraine has arguably more military hardware than ever before thanks to international aid. Since the start of the invasion, Ukraine has received tens of billions of dollars worth of military aid from Western allies like the United States, the United Kingdom, and Germany.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Ukrainian forces recapture village of Piatykhatky in counteroffensive against Russian invasion — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.politico.eu/article/ukraine-counteroffensive-war-russia-invasion-piatykhatky-zaporizhzhia-vladimir-putin-peace-talks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;POLITICO Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Ukrainian forces have recaptured the village of Piatykhatky in the southern Zaporizhzhia region, marking one of Ukraine&amp;#39;s first wins since the start of the counteroffensive against Russia&amp;#39;s invasion of the country. The UK Defense Ministry said that &amp;quot;heavy fighting has continued&amp;quot; with Ukraine making small advances in the Zaporizhzhia Oblast, western Donetsk Oblast, and around Bakhmut. The Ukrainian military also said that it had destroyed a &amp;quot;significant&amp;quot; ammunition depot near the Russian-occupied port city of Henichesk in the southern region of Kherson. Russian President Vladimir Putin predicted on Friday that Ukraine had &amp;quot;no chance&amp;quot; of success in this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Austrian intelligence agency prevents Islamist terror attack on Vienna gay pride parade — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/4fd671dc-9aee-4709-b081-059b0051640d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Austria&amp;#39;s intelligence agency has prevented an Islamist terror attack on Vienna&amp;#39;s annual gay pride parade. Three male suspects, Austrian citizens of Bosnian and Chechen heritage aged 14, 17 and 20, were apprehended by a Swat team after attempts to undertake &amp;quot;preparatory actions&amp;quot; for an attack. The plotters had been kept under &amp;quot;constant surveillance&amp;quot; and were allegedly planning to attack participants in the parade with weapons, including air guns, sabres and axes that were seized by police, as well as possibly using a car to drive into the crowd. The suspects had been radicalised online, with the DSN monitoring their consumption of Isis-linked propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=22d65c8f-005e-4c2d-9fa9-13e07bea438c&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 18 日，星期日 — 2 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>印度的糖尿病危机和疟疾传感器在预防策略方面取得突破</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-june-18-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-june-18-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 15:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-18T15:03:20Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 920 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/18cb4897-9639-41d8-ab12-2510279eea4e/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events and recaps, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Over a quarter of India&amp;#39;s population is diabetic or pre-diabetic, study finds — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/diabetes-obesity-hypertension-8670730/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Indian Express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A study by the Madras Diabetes Research Foundation and Indian Council of Medical Research has found that over a quarter of India&amp;#39;s population is either diabetic or in the pre-diabetic stage, with 101 million people living with diabetes and another 136 million in the pre-diabetes stage. The study also found that 35.5% of the population has hypertension, 28.6% is obese according to BMI measures, and 39.5% has abdominal obesity. The study is one of the largest ever attempted, with over 113,000 participants across 31 states and union territories in the country, and is highly representative of the Indian population. The findings can be used by states to develop health policies to target non-communicable diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] New malaria sensor discovery could lead to improved prevention strategies — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.techexplorist.com/disorient-malaria-parasite-prevent-harm/62346/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Tech Explorist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Scientists at the University of Geneva have discovered a new form of sensor that allows the Plasmodium genus microorganism, which causes malaria, to know exactly where it is and what to do. The sensor is made up of five proteins and enables the parasite to detect the presence of tiny molecules lacking in the blood but present in the mosquito when a mosquito consumes it. The study suggests that scrambling the signals this sensor sees could disorient the parasite and inhibit its proliferation and spread. Malaria is a major public health issue, especially in Sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Here are yesterday’s poll results. The question was: &lt;b&gt;Do you want to occasionally see the least significant news stories in the newsletter?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/0faf0b68-1a81-43d2-b976-e7ae10e279ac/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;While slightly more people voted Yes, I think we’d need an overwhelming majority to agree, since it goes against the project’s promise. I’ll leave these stories out of the email, but they will still be available on the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=f8c740cb-f580-4579-8484-1cf5eb8d0ae1&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 17 日，星期六 — 1 个重大新闻故事 + 实验</title>
<description>俄罗斯向白俄罗斯部署核武器</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-june-17-1-significant-news-story-experiment</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-june-17-1-significant-news-story-experiment</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 14:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-17T14:26:23Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 936 top news stories and gave 1 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/c7251f07-74b3-4cba-8919-97c800365ae3/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[8.1] Russian President deploys tactical nuclear weapons to Belarus as a warning to the West — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.straitstimes.com/world/europe/putin-says-russia-positions-nuclear-bombs-in-belarus-as-warning-to-west" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin has confirmed that he has deployed tactical nuclear weapons to Belarus, marking Moscow&amp;#39;s first deployment of such warheads outside Russia since the fall of the Soviet Union. Putin said that the move was intended as a warning to the West about arming and supporting Ukraine, and that it was a reminder that the West could not inflict a strategic defeat on Russia. The US has criticised Putin&amp;#39;s decision, but has said it has no intention of altering its own stance on strategic nuclear weapons and has not seen any signs that Russia is preparing to use a nuclear weapon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A little experiment. Here’s the &lt;b&gt;least&lt;/b&gt; significant news from yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[1.4] Three men occupy table without eating at busy food court — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://stomp.straitstimes.com/singapore-seen/diner-upset-by-group-of-3-who-took-up-food-court-table-to-play-games-during-busy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;STOMP&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A video taken by a Singaporean Stomper shows three men playing games on their mobile phones while seated at a dining table in a crowded food court. The group did not have any food or drinks on the table, and despite the lunch crowd, they did not give up their seats to those waiting for a table. The incident occurred at the newly-opened Sinfoodie food court at Tai Seng Street, which is known to be very busy during lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=b67aabb3-8fa4-46f7-b485-5bd4bb22715c&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 16 日星期五——项目更新和 2 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>脊髓灰质炎疫苗接种的进展、国际货币基金组织的欧元区经济建议</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-june-16-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-june-16-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-16T14:24:14Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Two quick project updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;1. News categories that were previously a part of the premium subscription, are now free. You can filter news with 9 categories: world, nation, general, business, science, technology, health, entertainment, and sports. Check them out here: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;2. Premium subscribers can create their own daily brief, by selecting how many articles they want to read overall and in each category. This is the last step before personalized emails. See the video demo here: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/premium#personal-feed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com/premium#personal-feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Back to the news…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1107 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/9d6cbcf3-a4a3-4611-a364-57006fcb196b/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] New polio vaccines developed to bolster global eradication efforts — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.openaccessgovernment.org/new-polio-vaccines-globally-eradicate-disease-nopv2/161109/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Open Access Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Scientists have developed two new oral polio vaccines, the first in five decades, aiming to reduce the risk of harmful mutations. This innovation comes in response to the persistent threat of polio, a debilitating disease particularly affecting children. These vaccines, when combined with an existing version, could provide lifelong protection against all strains of polio, potentially leading to its eradication. Human trials are in progress to confirm these vaccines&amp;#39; safety and effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] IMF urges ECB to raise rates and eurozone governments to cut deficits to combat inflation — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-needs-still-higher-ecb-rates-tighter-fiscal-policy-imf-2023-06-16/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has urged the European Central Bank (ECB) to continue raising rates to bring down inflation, and for eurozone governments to cut budget deficits to help it. The IMF also called on EU governments to agree on a reform of the bloc&amp;#39;s fiscal and debt rules that underpin the value of the euro. The ECB raised borrowing costs to their highest level in 22 years on Thursday and said stubbornly high inflation all but guaranteed another move next month and likely beyond that too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=60ddfed6-6a6e-42f4-a34d-2d548c48a0ab&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 15 日，星期四 — 3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>武汉实验室新冠病毒起源、前所未有的海水温度上升以及不断升级的全球登革热危机</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-june-15-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-june-15-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-15T13:54:28Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1116 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/fdd4c27e-0ac2-4d49-8970-16493afbf996/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[8.7] &amp;quot;Patient zero&amp;quot; identified among Wuhan Institute of Virology scientists — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.perthnow.com.au/news/coronavirus/trio-of-scientists-at-wuhan-lab-named-as-covids-patients-zero-after-conducting-risky-virus-research-c-10986756" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;PerthNow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Three scientists from the Wuhan Institute of Virology have been identified as the first individuals infected with the coronavirus, potentially marking them as &amp;quot;patients zero&amp;quot;. This information, coming from US government sources, supports the theory that the virus could have originated from a laboratory incident in Wuhan. These scientists had worked closely with Dr. Shi Zhengli, who collected samples of viruses from wildlife, including viruses similar to SARS-CoV-2, the virus causing COVID-19. This revelation provides fresh perspective on the debate surrounding the origins of the virus, previously widely believed to have crossed over to humans from animals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.8] Global sea surface temperatures spike beyond previous records, affecting North Atlantic — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/jun/15/from-the-oceans-to-net-zero-targets-were-in-denial-about-the-climate-crisis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Global sea surface temperatures have spiked beyond anything ever recorded since April, with the North Atlantic being particularly affected. The ocean has been absorbing most of the energy trapped by greenhouse gases humans have pumped into the atmosphere in recent decades, leading to ice melt, sea level rise, more intense cyclones, increased flooding risk and damage to marine life. A recent study found that a deep ocean current, known as the Southern Ocean overturning circulation, has already slowed by about a third since the 1990s, far more rapidly than forecast in climate models. The ramifications for regional and global temperatures and weather patterns will take time to unfold, but are expected to be substantial and cascading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Dengue now endemic in 129 countries, with worst outbreak currently affecting Peru — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://devpolicy.org/dengue-is-africa-ready-to-respond-20230615/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;devpolicy.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Dengue, the fastest spreading infectious disease in the world, is now endemic in 129 countries, with the worst outbreak currently affecting Peru. While 70% of cases are currently found in Asia, prevalence elsewhere is increasing due to anthropogenic factors including rapid urbanisation and globalisation. Africa has suffered Zika, chikungunya, yellow fever and multiple other mosquito-borne viruses, some of which have spread across the world and are causing increasingly frequent outbreaks, especially in urban situations where Aedes mosquitoes thrive. A lack of knowledge of healthcare workers on the symptoms of dengue, as well as an absence of a standardised case definition for reporting dengue cases, means many cases remain unreported or unconfirmed. Appropriate investment at a scale relative to the problem is essential to address this disease in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=6c9b937f-d304-4b4c-836c-c3bd12bdfc08&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 月 14 日星期三 — 3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>乌克兰流离失所危机、中国经济放缓期间降息、世界银行对发展中国家发出可怕警告</description>
<enclosure length="122256" type="image/png" url="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/96a08805-af63-4a0e-aadf-f3015b0f54af/template__3_.png"/>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-june-14-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-june-14-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-06-14T14:26:46Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1098 top news stories and gave 4 of them a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/0c3caaf2-af12-4367-b77b-1da8f7191453/pasted_image_0.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;After removing previously covered events, here is today’s significant news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.9] War in Ukraine leads to largest annual increase in forcibly displaced people in decades — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jun/14/ukraine-war-drove-biggest-rise-in-displaced-persons-in-decades" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The United Nations refugee agency has reported that the war in Ukraine has led to the largest annual increase of people forcibly displaced by persecution, conflict, violence and human rights violations in decades. The number of displaced people grew by 21% in 2022, standing at an estimated 108.4 million at the end of the year. The total number of refugees worldwide rose by a record 35%, or 8.9 million people, to reach 34.6 million. The increase was largely due to people from Ukraine, and revised estimates of Afghans in Iran and Pakistan. The war in Sudan and the ongoing invasion of Russia are the biggest drivers of the growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] People&amp;#39;s Bank of China cuts seven-day reverse repurchase rate to 1.9% amid economic slowdown — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/06/14/china-is-seen-to-be-kicking-off-a-new-cycle-of-rate-cuts.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The People&amp;#39;s Bank of China has cut its seven-day reverse repurchase rate from 2% to 1.9%, the first cut in nine months, as the economy loses momentum and hard data starts to disappoint. Economists view the move as the start of much more easing to come, with Barclays predicting China will deliver a cut for every quarter until early 2024. China&amp;#39;s new bank loans for May rose by 11.4% to 1.36 trillion yuan ($190 billion), missing estimates from a Reuters poll and strengthening the case for further stimulus, as the economy continues to see tumbling industrial profits on soft demand and falling exports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] World Bank report warns of dire consequences for emerging and developing countries due to polycrisis — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/3bd28362-c006-44c3-9f7f-a89a78452600" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The World Bank&amp;#39;s latest Global Economic Prospects report highlights the dire consequences of a &amp;quot;polycrisis&amp;quot; that has adversely affected emerging and developing countries, particularly the most vulnerable people within them. The report indicates that by the end of 2024, economic activity in these economies is expected to be about 5% below levels projected on the eve of the pandemic. In more than one-third of the poorest countries, incomes per head will be below 2019 levels in 2024. The reduction in global inequality seems to have stalled, and the long-term accumulation of debt, especially by low-income countries, is interacting with higher interest rates and turbulent credit markets to create serious debt difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;News Minimalist&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=8f44b4d7-52c6-43a7-9e46-662750ebeec6&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>









</channel>
</rss>