<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<description>Daily top news from newsminimalist.com. Read by 7000 minimalists.</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
<atom:link href="https://rss.beehiiv.com/feeds/4aF2pGVAEN.xml" rel="self"/>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 5 Oct 2023 15:50:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-05T15:50:01Z</atom:published>
<atom:updated>2023-10-05T15:50:02Z</atom:updated>
<category>News</category>
<category>Society</category>
<category>World</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2023, News Minimalist daily</copyright>
<image>
<url>https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/publication/logo/d0318cb6-0493-4e34-b055-76456e6c0f76/u1f422_u1f30d.png</url>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
</image>
<docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>beehiiv</generator>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>support@beehiiv.com (Beehiiv Support)</webMaster>
<item>
<title>10 月 5 日，星期四 — 破纪录的全球气温、南美季风风险、两栖动物数量减少、经济衰退警告、Meta 的人工智能工具、Android 14、诺贝尔化学奖</title>
<description>破纪录的全球气温、南美季风风险、两栖动物减少、经济衰退警告、Meta 的人工智能工具、Android 14、诺贝尔化学奖</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-october-5-record-breaking-global-temperatures-south-american-monsoon-risk-amphibian-decline</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-october-5-record-breaking-global-temperatures-south-american-monsoon-risk-amphibian-decline</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-05T15:50:01Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Today’s news prompted me to run a poll on environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;This category mainly features articles on trends and projections, and &lt;b&gt;excludes &lt;/b&gt;short-term and extreme natural disasters like wildfires.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Many articles will address rising temperatures and climate change, but also other environmental issues, like chemical management, air pollution, and plastics pollution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1195 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 7 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/5f1bdf0b-66c7-4691-a976-330f204732cf/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[8.5] September 2023: Record-breaking global temperatures, urgent need to reduce emissions. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/05/gobsmackingly-bananas-scientists-stunned-by-planets-record-september-heat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Global temperatures in September 2023 reached a new record, surpassing the previous record by 0.5°C, the largest jump in temperature ever seen. September was about 1.8°C warmer than pre-industrial levels, driven by high carbon dioxide emissions and the El Niño climate phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] South American monsoon at risk due to deforestation and global heating. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/04/south-american-monsoon-heading-towards-tipping-point-likely-to-cause-amazon-dieback" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The South American monsoon, which plays a crucial role in determining the climate of the continent, is approaching a &amp;quot;critical destabilisation point&amp;quot; due to deforestation in the Amazon and global heating, according to a study published in Science Advances. The study warns that if the tipping point is reached, it could result in up to 30% less rainfall, a dieback of the forest, and a severe impact on food production. The researchers urge policymakers to take urgent action to prevent this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Climate change causing decline of amphibians, most threatened vertebrate group. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2023/10/04/frog-climate-amphibians-extinction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;A major study published in the journal Nature has found that rising global temperatures due to climate change have become the primary reason for the decline of over 100 amphibian species between 2004 and 2022. Amphibians are particularly vulnerable to climate change as they lack the ability to regulate their temperature and moisture levels in a hotter and more drought-stricken world. Over 2 in 5 amphibian species are at risk of extinction, making them the most threatened group of vertebrates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Unctad warns central banks of recession risk, calls for pro-growth approach. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/oct/04/central-banks-risk-global-recession-unless-they-relax-inflation-targets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (Unctad) has warned that central banks risk pushing the global economy into a recession unless they relax their 2% inflation targets and adopt a more pro-growth stance. Unctad pointed to evidence of a looming debt crisis in poor countries, stating that the sharp rises in interest rates from major central banks since 2021 have increased inequality and reduced investment without effectively combating inflation. The report also highlighted that global growth is expected to slow from 3% in 2022 to 2.4% in 2023, with little sign of a rebound next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Meta Platforms introduces generative AI tools for advertisers. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/meta-starts-rolling-out-generative-ai-tools-all-advertisers-2023-10-04/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Meta Platforms, the parent company of Facebook and Instagram, has announced that it is rolling out generative AI tools for advertisers. These tools, which can create content like image backgrounds and variations of written text, were tested earlier this year and will be available in Meta&amp;#39;s Ads Manager by next year. This move marks Meta&amp;#39;s first step into incorporating generative AI technology into its products for generating new content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Android 14: Customization, accessibility, and privacy updates for supported devices. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/10/04/android-14-new-lock-screen-customization-options-accessibility-features-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Google has unveiled Android 14 at its Made By Google event, introducing new customization options and accessibility features. The update is rolling out to supported Pixel devices today and will be available on other devices later this year. Android 14 includes features such as an updated customization picker, AI-generated wallpapers, improved photo and camera quality, enhanced accessibility options for low-vision and hard-of-hearing users, and more control over data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Nobel Prize awarded for quantum dot discovery with various applications. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/science/bawendi-brus-ekimov-win-2023-nobel-prize-chemistry-2023-10-04/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Scientists Moungi Bawendi, Louis Brus, and Alexei Ekimov have been awarded the 2023 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for their discovery of quantum dots, which are now used in flat screens, LED lamps, and medical imaging devices. The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences stated that their findings have great potential in various fields, including flexible electronics, sensors, solar cells, and quantum communication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=c81ae0b4-4d54-4dbe-9787-c32df5cbcefa&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>10 月 4 日星期三 — 2 条重大新闻报道：全球债券抛售、气候对公共健康的影响</title>
<description>全球债券抛售、气候对公共健康的影响</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-october-4-2-significant-news-stories-global-bond-sell-off-climate-impact-on-public-health</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-october-4-2-significant-news-stories-global-bond-sell-off-climate-impact-on-public-health</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 15:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-04T15:57:25Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(45, 45, 45);font-family:Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;font-size:16px;"&gt;Today’s poll is about business and technology.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(45, 45, 45);font-family:Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;font-size:16px;"&gt;I put these together because they are often interconnected. Only news about the biggest companies gets a high enough score for the newsletter, and almost all of the biggest companies specialize in tech: Apple, Microsoft, Google, Amazon, Nvidia, Tesla, Meta.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;But this category &lt;b&gt;is not exclusive to tech&lt;/b&gt;: think biggest car manufacturers, fast food chains, banks, and companies in energy, retail, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The news might cover new products and services, but also lawsuits, labor strikes, and product recalls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1273 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 2 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/a735d83c-b05d-48c3-bce5-edd14a12015b/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.7] Global bond markets sell-off as interest rates rise, impacting various sectors. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/global-markets-bond-selloff-graphic-2023-10-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Global bond markets are experiencing a sell-off as interest rates rise. In the US Treasury market, 10-year bond yields have reached 16-year highs, while in Germany they are at their highest since the 2011 euro zone debt crisis. The rise in bond yields has implications for mortgage rates, loan rates, government funding costs, and global markets, with emerging markets particularly vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.6] Climate change is reversing public health gains and increasing disease rates. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/03/climate/the-climate-crisis-is-also-a-health-crisis.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The New York Times&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(55, 65, 81);font-family:Söhne, ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, Segoe UI, Roboto, Ubuntu, Cantarell, Noto Sans, sans-serif, Helvetica Neue, Arial, Apple Color Emoji, Segoe UI Emoji, Segoe UI Symbol, Noto Color Emoji;font-size:16px;"&gt;Despite advancements in healthcare and disease treatment, climate change is posing a significant threat to public health. Malaria deaths, which had decreased to fewer than 600,000 in 2021 from about 900,000 in 2000, are rising again due to the expansion of warm habitats suitable for disease-carrying mosquitoes. A recent study noted that more than two billion people were exposed to fire-related air pollution annually between 2010 and 2019, reversing some gains made against respiratory diseases. Climate change is also linked to increased instances of heat waves, wildfires, and floods, affecting public health on multiple fronts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=3849d613-8e83-42d9-bab3-1613c2dc85ee&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>10 月 3 日星期二 — 4 条重大新闻报道：苏丹冲突、孟加拉国登革热疫情、自闭症检测应用程序和牛津抗疟疾疫苗</title>
<description>苏丹冲突、孟加拉国登革热疫情、自闭症检测应用程序和牛津抗疟疾疫苗</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-october-3-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-october-3-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-03T17:01:39Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thank you for your responses yesterday. I’m especially grateful for your comments, as they help me understand the Why behind the vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;There is one concern with the polls I’ve seen several times. I’ll quote one reader, as I can’t say it better:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="blockquote"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="blockquote__quote"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(34, 34, 34);font-family:Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:small;"&gt;My feedback is that I like that users aren’t shaping the algorithm, I like that it finds what it finds. When our preferences shape the findings it seems to reduce the value of the algorithm because then we just get what we want/expect. For me, the beauty of what you’ve created is that it finds importance in sometimes unlikely places. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption class="blockquote__byline"&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I agree. I don’t want the project to become another news service focused entirely on user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;But the project as it is today was heavily shaped by users. The first version only had 3 parameters: scale, magnitude, and potential. Over months the most passionate readers found the flaws in the algorithm: too much sensationalism (I added credibility parameter), too many unconfirmed predictions (immediacy), already known facts (novelty), unactionable news (actionability).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I also changed the weights of the parameters several times before. Too much novelty led to a science-heavy feed. Too much actionability and we start to see articles like “WhatsApp released stickers, try them now!”. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;These polls won’t fundamentally change the direction of a project. They’ll just help us continue doing what we’ve already been doing before, but better — in addition to listening to the most passionate readers, they’ll let me listen to all of you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Today’s poll is about public health: outbreaks, new treatments and vaccines, health studies, health trends, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1313 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/8758f4b7-845a-4b0d-a007-fd0da5515c37/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Conflict in Sudan displaces millions, strains aid efforts, and worsens violence. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/oct/03/sudan-conflict-like-planning-for-the-apocalypse-say-aid-workers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The escalating conflict in Sudan has disrupted aid supply lines and led to a growing number of internally displaced people and refugees. At least 5.4 million people have been displaced since the fighting began in April, with communal violence erupting in the Darfur region. Humanitarian officials are struggling to respond to the crisis, with one official describing it as trying to &amp;quot;plan for the apocalypse.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Bangladesh&amp;#39;s dengue outbreak kills over 1,000, infects 209,000. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/bangladesh-dengue-deaths-top-1000-worst-outbreak-2023-10-02/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;According to official data, the death toll from Bangladesh&amp;#39;s worst dengue outbreak on record has surpassed 1,000 this year, with nearly 209,000 people infected. This makes 2023 the deadliest year for dengue in Bangladesh since the first recorded epidemic in 2000. Hospitals are struggling to accommodate the large number of patients, and there is a shortage of intravenous fluids.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Tablet app improves early detection of autism spectrum disorder. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nih.gov/news-events/news-releases/digital-autism-screening-tool-shows-promise-nih-funded-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;National Institutes of Health (.gov)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;A tablet-based screening application for autism spectrum disorder (ASD) has shown promise in improving early detection, according to a study funded by the National Institutes of Health. The app demonstrated 87.8% sensitivity in detecting ASD and 80.8% specificity in identifying children without the condition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] WHO approves Oxford&amp;#39;s anti-malaria vaccine, reduces cases by 75%. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2023/10/03/malaria-vaccine-r21-oxford/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The World Health Organization has approved a new anti-malaria vaccine developed by Oxford University. The R21/Matrix-M vaccine is the second vaccine to be recommended by the WHO and has shown to reduce symptomatic cases by 75% in areas with high seasonal malaria transmission. The vaccine is expected to be available by mid-2024 at a cost of $2-4 per dose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=ccb371f6-3b6a-44e0-a937-9f6940786b70&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>10 月 2 日星期一 — 3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>诺贝尔奖mRNA疫苗、恒大危机、中国西部紧张局势</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-october-2-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-october-2-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 15:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-02T15:58:13Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for all the replies yesterday!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Quick reminder: this week I’ll be asking you to share your relationship with different news categories (&lt;a class="link" href="https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-october-1-3-significant-news-stories" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;announcement post&lt;/a&gt;). I’ll share the results at the end and will use them to fine-tune the weights of scoring factors: scale, magnitude, etc. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today, we’re looking at disasters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1209 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/ae47959a-54a2-4d09-8305-018a7819909f/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.7] Evergrande&amp;#39;s crisis deepens with chairman under investigation, stock trading halted. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-chairman-investigated-over-offshore-asset-transfers-wsj-2023-10-02/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;China Evergrande Group, a prominent real estate developer in China, is facing serious financial troubles, and its Chairman, Hui Ka Yan, is under investigation for allegedly transferring assets unlawfully. The company is in the midst of restructuring its substantial debts and is struggling to complete several projects. With liabilities exceeding $300 billion, Evergrande&amp;#39;s crisis is reflective of larger instability in China&amp;#39;s real estate market. Consequently, trading in Evergrande’s stocks has been temporarily halted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] Tensions between West and China impact global markets and supply chains. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/how-china-west-tensions-will-shape-global-markets-2023-10-02/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Escalating tensions between the West and China are significantly impacting global markets, reshaping supply chains and causing elevated inflation and interest rates. The divergence has led to “friendshoring,” with nations like India, Vietnam, and Mexico benefiting from a U.S. supply chain shift. India’s stocks have surged 8% this year, indicating a favorable economic environment amid tensions. Meanwhile, heightened scrutiny in China has affected Western luxury sector shares, experiencing a 16% slide in Q3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[9.0] Katalin Karikó and Drew Weissman awarded Nobel for vaccine breakthrough. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/02/health/nobel-prize-medicine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Katalin Karikó and Drew Weissman, who made a breakthrough discovery in tweaking the structure of messenger RNA (mRNA) that led to the development of Covid-19 vaccines, have been awarded the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine. Their research showed that by slightly altering mRNA, it could be used to instruct cells to produce specific proteins, eliminating the need for modified viruses in vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=77a28da5-c42c-4cfb-99b9-aafb9f57d223&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>10 月 1 日（星期日）——3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>全球化学品管理目标、欧盟碳关税、葡萄牙住房抗议</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-october-1-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-october-1-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 16:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-10-01T16:32:06Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Hey! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Quick poll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I don’t affect the ChatGPT scores in any way and my prompt to it is intentionally as vague as possible to not introduce human bias. But the weights of the score factors are defined by your feedback. For example, what should have a higher score: a science article with scale 5 and novelty 9, or a natural disaster article with scale 9 and novelty 5?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Previously I adjusted the weights based on individual emails from some of you. But I think it’s time to do it properly and get the feedback from the entire audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;So over the next week or so I will be asking you the same question about different news categories: economy, environment, science, etc. Let me know what you think — your answers will define what you read here every day. I’ll analyze and share the results after we cover all categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Let’s start with the economy:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thank you! Back to news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1060 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/378ae38b-7aab-4156-8fa7-7f73f390548b/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] Global framework sets targets to improve chemical management and reduce pollution. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/09/1141717" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;UN News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The Global Framework on Chemicals, agreed upon at the fifth International Conference on Chemicals Management, sets 28 concrete targets to improve the responsible management of chemicals and waste. The framework aims to reduce chemical pollution by 2030, phase out highly hazardous pesticides in agriculture by 2035, and establish stronger connections with other global agendas such as climate change and human rights. The Bonn Declaration, also adopted at the conference, aims to prevent exposure to harmful chemicals, enhance safe management, and support the transition to circular economies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] EU launches carbon tariffs on imported goods to promote greener production. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/eu-launches-first-phase-worlds-first-carbon-border-tariff-2023-09-30/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The European Union has launched the first phase of the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), which aims to impose CO2 emissions tariffs on imported steel, cement, and other goods. The CBAM will require EU importers to report greenhouse gas emissions embedded in imported products, and from 2026, importers will need to purchase certificates to cover these emissions. The goal of the CBAM is to encourage greener production worldwide and prevent European manufacturers from relocating to countries with lower environmental standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Protests in Portugal against high rents and housing crisis. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/tent-dwelling-migrants-join-protest-over-portugals-housing-prices-2023-09-30/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thousands of Portuguese citizens, including migrants and precarious workers, took part in protests against soaring rents and house prices in Portugal, which has been exacerbated by growing gentrification and record tourism. Since the start of the tourism boom in 2015, Lisbon rents have increased by 65%, making apartments unaffordable for many, while sale prices have skyrocketed by 137%. The housing crisis has particularly affected migrants, with nearly 38% of Portugal&amp;#39;s foreign population living in overcrowded households, and many facing discrimination in access to housing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;(not a 7+ article, but concludes the government shutdown story)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[4.8] Biden signs bill to keep government funded and avoid shutdown. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/4232249-biden-signs-bill-to-keep-government-funded-and-avoid-shutdown/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Hill&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;President Biden signed a Continuing Resolution on Saturday night, effectively preventing a government shutdown just before the midnight deadline. This temporary measure, which received broad support in both the House and Senate, extends the government&amp;#39;s current spending levels until mid-November. The bill includes $16 billion for disaster relief but omits aid for Ukraine or modifications to border policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=4201b13b-74aa-414c-bab2-cadce492494c&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 30 日星期六——7 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>纽约市山洪暴发、政府关门迫在眉睫、俄罗斯的西方公司、荷兰的蓝舌病毒、现代和起亚召回、霍乱病例翻倍、FDA批准基因检测</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-september-30-7-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-september-30-7-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 15:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-30T15:18:01Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1130 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 7 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/738a9300-6319-478d-bfd1-8a98ebac2efe/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] Flash flooding hits NYC, State of Emergency declared, widespread warnings. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/nyc-flooding-subway-weather-mta-b2421042.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;New York City has been hit by flash flooding caused by torrential rain, leading to a State of Emergency being declared by Governor Kathy Hochul. Videos have emerged showing streets and subways in Brooklyn underwater. The area has already seen between two and five inches of rain, with more expected, leading to widespread flood watches and warnings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] House rejects 30-day funding bill, federal shutdown likely Sunday. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/hardline-republican-holdouts-push-us-government-closer-shutdown-2023-09-29/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reuters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;In a 232-198 vote, the U.S. House of Representatives rejected a bill aiming to temporarily extend government funding by 30 days, thereby increasing the likelihood of a federal shutdown starting on Sunday. The defeated bill proposed cuts in spending and restrictions on immigration — measures favored by Republicans but unlikely to pass the Democratic-controlled Senate. If funding isn&amp;#39;t extended past 12:01 a.m. ET on Sunday, the impact could be substantial: closure of national parks, disruption of pay for up to 4 million federal workers, and hindrance of financial oversight to scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Restrictive regulations and moral dilemmas for Western companies in Russia. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/7ec7731d-194a-4615-994a-b1dde6060122" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Western companies operating in Russia are facing an increasingly restrictive regulatory environment and the moral dilemma of participating in Russia&amp;#39;s wartime economy. The Kremlin has imposed a ban on dividends to businesses from countries deemed &amp;quot;unfriendly&amp;quot;, and if companies want to sell their assets, they must receive approval from the Kremlin, which imposes a minimum 50% discount on the value of the assets sold and requires a 10% &amp;quot;voluntary&amp;quot; contribution to the state budget. The Kyiv School of Economics estimates that companies from the US, UK, and EU amassed $18bn in Russian profits and $199bn in revenues in 2022 alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Bluetongue virus outbreak affects hundreds of farms in the Netherlands. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/hundreds-dutch-farms-grappling-with-bluetongue-virus-government-says-2023-09-29/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;An outbreak of the bluetongue virus has affected hundreds of farms in the Netherlands, according to the Dutch government. Up to 600 farms may already be contaminated, with the first four cases of the highly infectious animal disease reported this month. The outbreak will limit the export of cows and sheep from the Netherlands as animals will need to be tested or quarantined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Hyundai and Kia recall 3.4 million vehicles in US and Canada. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/29/business/hyundai-kia-recall-fire.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Hyundai and Kia are recalling nearly 3.4 million vehicles in the US due to the risk of a fire in the engine compartment caused by a brake fluid leak. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration has advised car owners to park their vehicles outside. Additionally, 600,000 Hyundai and Kia vehicles in Canada are also being recalled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Cholera cases double globally, vaccine shortages impact vaccination regimen. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2023/09/30/cholera-cases-doubled-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;According to a new analysis by the World Health Organization, the number of cholera cases worldwide doubled from 2021 to 2022, with 44 countries reporting cases. The largest outbreaks, with over 10,000 documented or suspected cases, occurred in Afghanistan, Cameroon, Democratic Republic of Congo, Malawi, Nigeria, Somalia, and Syria. In 2022, there were a total of 472,697 cases and 2,349 deaths from cholera globally. Vaccine shortages and the rising outbreak rate have reduced the availability of oral cholera vaccines, leading the WHO to suspend its two-dose vaccination regimen and replace it with a single-dose regimen to stretch existing stockpiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] FDA approves Invitae&amp;#39;s genetic test for common hereditary cancers. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-grants-first-marketing-authorization-dna-test-assess-predisposition-dozens-cancer-types" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;FDA.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The U.S. Food and Drug Administration has granted marketing authorization for the Invitae Common Hereditary Cancers Panel, an in vitro diagnostic test that can detect genetic variants associated with an elevated risk of developing certain cancers. The test evaluates DNA from a blood sample to identify variants in 47 genes linked to an increased risk of cancer. It is the first test of its kind to receive FDA marketing authorization and can provide individuals with more information about their health and guide physicians in monitoring and potential therapy based on the discovered variants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=73f9cb0b-f7e3-4a9b-ae0f-8c556ae54a49&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 29 日星期五——4 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>马斯克解散了 X 的选举保障团队、加州每小时 20 美元的快餐工资、SEC 对以太坊期货 ETF 的认可、深入了解阿尔茨海默氏症的分子基础</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-29-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-29-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-29T14:07:24Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1223 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/2b10bcbb-d08e-458c-9f7f-1a5009a01cbd/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Elon Musk disbands team working on election disinformation prevention. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/28/elon-musk-ditches-x-twitter-election-integrity-team-key-votes-disinformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Elon Musk has disbanded the team at X (formerly known as Twitter) that was working to prevent disruption to elections, just days after the EU announced that the platform had the highest proportion of disinformation in three European countries. Several staff members, including the co-lead of the election disinformation team, have left the company. Musk&amp;#39;s decision has raised concerns about the platform&amp;#39;s approach to content moderation and brand safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] California raises minimum wage for fast food workers to $20/hr. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://apnews.com/article/california-minimum-wage-increase-fast-food-newsom-69c26b7f07f2647149c37677446cea30" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Associated Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;California&amp;#39;s Governor Gavin Newsom has enacted a law raising the minimum wage for fast food workers to $20 per hour starting next year, recognizing these employees as primary earners in many low-income households. The state&amp;#39;s general minimum wage, at $15.50 per hour, is already one of the highest in the country. The law applies to fast-food chains with a minimum of 60 locations nationwide and will impact restaurants that currently pay workers an average of $16.60 per hour. The law also establishes a Fast Food Council which can further increase wages annually until 2029.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Valkyrie Funds obtains SEC approval for Ethereum futures in ETF. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/valkyrie-funds-add-ether-futures-exchange-traded-fund-after-sec-approval-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Valkyrie Funds LLC, an investment management firm, has gained approval from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to introduce ethereum futures to its existing Bitcoin futures ETF, creating the Valkyrie Bitcoin and Ether Strategy ETF available from Monday. This is the first time investors can access Ethereum-based futures via an ETF, marking a significant milestone for the cryptocurrency market. Rival firms VanEck and ProShares have also been authorized to launch similar offerings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] MIT researchers analyze Alzheimer&amp;#39;s brains, identify genetic and molecular foundations. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://neurosciencenews.com/alzhiemers-genetics-23991/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Neuroscience News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;MIT researchers have conducted the most comprehensive study yet on Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease, examining over 2 million brain cells from 400 deceased patients. Their findings suggest that Alzheimer&amp;#39;s is not just influenced by one factor but is a complex interplay of genetic and lifestyle changes. In addition to discovering that certain brain cells known as &amp;quot;inhibitory neurons&amp;quot; could be crucial in resisting the disease, they also found that immune cells in the brain, called microglia, exacerbate the condition by adopting inflammatory states. Moreover, as neurons age, their ability to repair DNA diminishes, further accelerating the disease. The team is exploring AI technologies to find new treatments based on these insights, offering a fresh approach to combatting Alzheimer&amp;#39;s beyond the traditional focus on brain plaques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=d50fc728-076a-4fb5-adb7-c6af457680bd&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 28 日，星期四 — 主要更新和 2 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>与中国有关的网络威胁；纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫大规模逃亡</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-september-28-major-update-and-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-september-28-major-update-and-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 15:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-28T15:23:47Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Hey everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I have a big and exciting update to share. It’s longer than usual, so I put it after the news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1190 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 2 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/78ef8b3a-8a9e-4661-ba5f-792ec1e99066/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.7] U.S. and Japanese agencies warn companies about China-linked hacker group BlackTech. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-japan-authorities-warn-china-linked-hacking-group-blacktech-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The U.S. National Security Agency, Federal Bureau of Investigation, and Japanese police have issued a joint advisory warning multinational companies about the China-linked hacker group BlackTech. The advisory urged companies to review their internet routers to minimize the risk of potential attacks from the group, which has been engaging in cyberattacks on governments and tech-sector companies since around 2010. The advisory comes amid heightened tensions between the U.S. and China over cybersecurity issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Mass exodus of ethnic Armenians from Nagorno-Karabakh after Azerbaijan takeover. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/more-than-half-armenians-nagorno-karabakh-have-left-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;More than half of the 120,000 ethnic Armenians in Nagorno-Karabakh have fled the region in less than four days after Azerbaijan took control, marking an unprecedented exodus in the South Caucasus. Azerbaijan has stated that it will respect ethnic Armenian rights, but due to historical tensions and fears of genocide and ethnic cleansing, many Armenians are leaving in fear. As of Thursday morning, over 65,000 people had crossed into neighboring Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Now, the update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adding live coverage and solving topic fatigue.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Three problems bugged News Minimalist website from the start: stale news, bad updates timing, and repetitive content. And I think I finally solved them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Problems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Since the very beginning of the project, the news was grouped by days. The algorithm collected news for 24 hours, rated all articles, and showed the results for the next 24 hours. The system was built around this newsletter that was sent daily. But it had three major problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;First, the news was becoming stale. Since the website was static for 24 hours, it considerably lagged behind the events by the end of that window. The problem was even worse than it appeared: since the website didn&amp;#39;t change for 24 hours after the update, in the worst-case scenario you could read news with a 48-hour delay!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Second, the website was updated too late for many parts of the world. If you&amp;#39;re in the Americas, the website was updated from 5 to 9 a.m. based on your timezone, letting you read fresh news in the morning. But for other parts of the world, the update came too late: around lunch for Europe and dinner in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The third problem was that deduplication only worked on news within 24 hours. The next day, the deduplication algorithm analyzed the entirely new batch of articles with no overlap. That led to people seeing news about the same event every day, leading to &amp;quot;topic fatigue&amp;quot; — where a single event is covered so much that it&amp;#39;s not interesting anymore and causes frustration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Solution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The first part of the solution is simple: News Minimalist switches to live coverage. Now the website is updated every hour, letting people learn about new events almost in real-time and when they find it convenient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;But the second part took me a long time to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The deduplication algorithm now works continuously, analyzing a sliding 72-hour window of articles instead of 24-hour non-overlapping batches. This extends the purpose of the algorithm: from finding plain duplicates, to organizing articles into &amp;quot;stories&amp;quot; covering one event. Now, the crucial part here is that stories are sorted by their start time: new stories at the top, and older at the bottom. Once the oldest article in a story falls out of the 72-hour window, it gets replaced by a slightly newer but still old article, keeping the story at the bottom. This should solve the issue of &amp;quot;topic fatigue&amp;quot; — something entirely new and unexpected must happen for an article to break away from the story and form a new story that would appear at the top. The older story will still be available at the bottom and will continue to give ongoing coverage of the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;This is still a bit raw. I will be adjusting the length of the window and the “closeness” of articles in one story over the next several weeks to improve the feed even more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I am very excited to share this — this is a new chapter for News Minimalist and I hope you’ll like it: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;https://www.newsminimalist.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thank you all,&lt;br&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=68490037-9f73-4ee8-95cd-64b1fdd7f183&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 27 日星期三——5 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>FTC 起诉亚马逊、欧盟对马斯克的警告、中国的应用商店法规、FCC 的网络中立复兴、久坐的生活方式风险</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-27-5-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-27-5-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 13:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-27T13:46:37Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1226 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 5 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/eb3a4778-9cff-4b83-8996-77adc672acb0/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.6] FTC files antitrust lawsuit against Amazon, alleging harm to consumers. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-sues-amazoncom-breaking-antitrust-law-harming-consumers-2023-09-26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has filed an antitrust lawsuit against Amazon, following a long-standing accusation of the company misusing its monopoly power and forcing sellers to use its services, thereby increasing costs. The lawsuit, supported by 17 state attorneys general, could potentially force Amazon to sell assets to restore fair competition. Amazon refutes these claims, suggesting that their practices spur innovation and competition within the retail industry, benefitting consumers and businesses. Amazon&amp;#39;s shares fell 4% after the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] EU warns Elon Musk to comply with new laws on fake news and Russian propaganda. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/26/eu-warns-elon-musk-that-twitter-x-must-comply-with-fake-news-laws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The EU has warned Elon Musk to comply with new laws on fake news and Russian propaganda after X (formerly known as Twitter) was found to have the highest ratio of disinformation posts among large social media platforms. Facebook was the second worst offender, according to a report on posts that will be deemed illegal under the Digital Services Act. While Facebook, Google, TikTok, and Microsoft have signed up to the EU&amp;#39;s code of practice, Twitter is obliged to comply with the new laws or face a ban across the EU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] China enforces new rules on mobile app stores, Apple excluded. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-enforces-new-filing-rules-smartphone-app-stores-2023-09-27/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;China&amp;#39;s cyberspace regulator has started enforcing new rules overseeing mobile apps, with 26 app stores, including those operated by Tencent, Huawei, and Samsung, submitting business details. However, Apple&amp;#39;s App Store is noticeably absent from the list. The heightened scrutiny, a part of Beijing&amp;#39;s expanding oversight of smartphone usage, mandates app stores and apps to report business details to the government, intensifying concerns about app publishing and availability in the country. Compliance could significantly impact the availability of apps in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Sitting for long hours increases dementia risk, exercise doesn&amp;#39;t help. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2023/09/27/sitting-sedentary-exercise-dementia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A recent study published in JAMA has revealed that prolonged sitting can significantly increase the risk of developing dementia, impacting even those who maintain regular exercise routines. The study, examining nearly 50,000 men and women aged 60 or above, found a strong correlation between sedentary behavior and the onset of dementia within seven years. Individuals seated for at least 10 hours daily had an 8% higher risk, escalating to 63% for those seated 12 hours or more. Contrarily, people sedentary for under 9.5 hours didn’t show any increased risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] FCC to reinstate net neutrality rules for equal internet treatment. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/09/26/fcc-announces-plans-to-reinstate-net-neutrality/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The FCC, led by Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, is working to reinstate net neutrality, requiring broadband providers to treat all internet traffic equally. This move would prevent providers from favoring their own services or those of business partners. Net neutrality had been overturned during the previous administration but is deemed essential for fair access to online resources. The renewed rules aim to classify broadband as a necessity, like water and power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=03214b59-8520-413c-a3cb-7b40d9a66823&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 26 日星期二——6 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>南极冰雪危机、Covid药物突变风险、“皮罗拉”变种、全球贸易衰退、错误信息政策转变、增强的ChatGPT</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-26-6-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-26-6-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-26T14:16:16Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1213 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 6 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/33ee04d5-a928-4f4c-8ced-d276e2b66980/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.9] Antarctic sea ice hits record low, raising climate change concerns. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/antarctic-winter-sea-ice-hits-record-low-sparking-climate-worries-2023-09-25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Antarctic sea ice reached record low levels this winter, according to the U.S. National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC), raising concerns about the impact of climate change on the region. The extent of sea ice peaked on September 10 at 16.96 million square kilometers, the lowest winter maximum since satellite records began in 1979. This is about 1 million square kilometers less than the previous winter record set in 1986. The reduction in sea ice can have negative consequences for animals like penguins and can also contribute to global warming by reducing the amount of sunlight reflected back into space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] COVID-19 drug molnupiravir may cause harmful virus mutations. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://thehill.com/policy/healthcare/4222003-potential-link-found-between-merck-antiviral-and-mutated-covid-strains/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A study published in the Nature science journal suggests that the COVID-19 antiviral drug molnupiravir, developed by Merck, may be linked to the emergence of new mutations of the virus. The researchers found that the drug induces high rates of mutations in the virus, with a &amp;quot;high proportion&amp;quot; of these mutations likely to be harmful to the virus. They also found that many of the mutations observed in sequenced COVID-19 genomes in 2022 were consistent with mutations found in patients treated with molnupiravir.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] New Covid variant &amp;quot;Pirola&amp;quot; with 30+ spike protein mutations detected. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/pirola-variant-symptoms-covid-b2418666.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A new Covid variant called &amp;quot;Pirola&amp;quot; is spreading in the United States and has more than 30 mutations to its spike protein compared to the XBB.1.5 variant of Omicron, according to Yale Medicine. The variant has been found in 10 states and has also been detected in several other countries. Experts are closely monitoring the variant and its potential impact on transmission and immunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Global trade volumes decline due to rising interest rates and inflation. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/36982601-b799-4166-9e6b-39533efbdfdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Global trade volumes fell at their fastest annual pace in almost three years in July, with a 3.2% decrease compared to the same month last year, according to the Netherlands Bureau for Economic Policy Analysis. The decline in trade volumes is seen as a result of rising interest rates impacting global demand for goods, as well as higher inflation and reduced spending on global goods exports. The figures suggest that global growth is slowing and sentiment indicators indicate that world trade will remain weak in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Tech platforms backtrack on misinformation policies, raising concerns for elections. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.straitstimes.com/world/united-states/us-tech-firms-roll-back-misinformation-curbs-ahead-of-2024-polls" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Tech platforms like YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter are rolling back policies aimed at curbing misinformation and falsehoods ahead of the upcoming global election season, raising concerns about their ability to tackle the expected deluge of misinformation during over 50 major elections next year. These changes come amidst layoffs, cost-cutting measures, and pressure from right-wing groups accusing the platforms of suppressing free speech. Critics argue that these moves have left democracies vulnerable to election interference, hate speech, and violent coup attempts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] ChatGPT gets voice and image support, bringing it closer to AI assistants like Siri. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/25/chatgpt-voice-update-siri-alexa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;OpenAI&amp;#39;s ChatGPT is receiving an update that will allow the chatbot to have voice conversations with users and interact using images, bringing it closer to popular AI assistants like Siri. The voice feature has various applications, including creative and accessibility-focused uses, while the image support enables users to troubleshoot, analyze data, and plan meals. The new features will be rolled out to subscribers of ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Plus and Enterprise plans in the next two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=cc0f18c0-b32e-4dcb-8021-7efb0f85e2dd&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 25 日星期一——3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>亚马逊的人工智能投资、欧洲的噪音污染、新加坡的二战炸弹</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-25-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-25-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-25T15:08:55Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1146 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/891c78e3-7ed2-4866-b52c-c87772d5b0de/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Amazon invests $4 billion in AI start-up Anthropic. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/25/business/amazon-anthropic-ai-deal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Amazon has announced plans to invest up to $4 billion in AI start-up Anthropic, known as one of the main competitors of OpenAI and operating a chatbot named Claude. Joining other tech giants like Microsoft and Google in the race, Amazon&amp;#39;s investment in Anthropic will leverage its data centers, cloud-computing platform, and AI chips. The investment will give Amazon a minority stake in the start-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] 1 in 5 Europeans exposed to harmful noise levels, health risks. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2023/sep/24/should-i-worry-about-noise-pollution" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;At least one in five Europeans are exposed to noise levels considered harmful to their health, according to the European Environment Agency (EEA), with that number projected to increase. In the UK alone, road, railway, and aircraft noise are estimated to cause over 6,000 new cases of ischaemic heart disease, 1,000 premature deaths, and 750,000 cases of sleep disturbance each year. Chronic noise exposure is also associated with increased risk for hypertension, strokes, and dementia, and noise pollution is a problem that society needs to address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Singapore residents evacuated due to WWII bomb detonation. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/more-than-4k-residents-and-1k-homes-affected-by-upper-bukit-timah-bomb-disposal-operation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;More than 4,000 residents in Singapore will have to evacuate their homes on Tuesday as a World War II era bomb is detonated nearby. The bomb, weighing 100kg, was found at a construction site and is too dangerous to move. This is the largest evacuation exercise involving the detonation of a WWII relic, with over 1,000 homes affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=5b44511b-10ce-42f3-8721-1c1f8faee864&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>









</channel>
</rss>