<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<description>Daily top news from newsminimalist.com. Read by 7000 minimalists.</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
<atom:link href="https://rss.beehiiv.com/feeds/4aF2pGVAEN.xml" rel="self"/>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:10:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-29T14:07:24Z</atom:published>
<atom:updated>2023-09-29T14:10:07Z</atom:updated>
<category>News</category>
<category>Society</category>
<category>World</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2023, News Minimalist daily</copyright>
<image>
<url>https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/publication/logo/d0318cb6-0493-4e34-b055-76456e6c0f76/u1f422_u1f30d.png</url>
<title>News Minimalist daily</title>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/</link>
</image>
<docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>beehiiv</generator>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>support@beehiiv.com (Beehiiv Support)</webMaster>
<item>
<title>9 月 29 日星期五——4 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>马斯克解散了 X 的选举保障团队、加州每小时 20 美元的快餐工资、SEC 对以太坊期货 ETF 的认可、深入了解阿尔茨海默病的分子基础</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-29-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-29-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-29T14:07:24Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1223 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/2b10bcbb-d08e-458c-9f7f-1a5009a01cbd/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Elon Musk disbands team working on election disinformation prevention. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/28/elon-musk-ditches-x-twitter-election-integrity-team-key-votes-disinformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Elon Musk has disbanded the team at X (formerly known as Twitter) that was working to prevent disruption to elections, just days after the EU announced that the platform had the highest proportion of disinformation in three European countries. Several staff members, including the co-lead of the election disinformation team, have left the company. Musk&amp;#39;s decision has raised concerns about the platform&amp;#39;s approach to content moderation and brand safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] California raises minimum wage for fast food workers to $20/hr. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://apnews.com/article/california-minimum-wage-increase-fast-food-newsom-69c26b7f07f2647149c37677446cea30" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Associated Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;California&amp;#39;s Governor Gavin Newsom has enacted a law raising the minimum wage for fast food workers to $20 per hour starting next year, recognizing these employees as primary earners in many low-income households. The state&amp;#39;s general minimum wage, at $15.50 per hour, is already one of the highest in the country. The law applies to fast-food chains with a minimum of 60 locations nationwide and will impact restaurants that currently pay workers an average of $16.60 per hour. The law also establishes a Fast Food Council which can further increase wages annually until 2029.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Valkyrie Funds obtains SEC approval for Ethereum futures in ETF. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/valkyrie-funds-add-ether-futures-exchange-traded-fund-after-sec-approval-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Valkyrie Funds LLC, an investment management firm, has gained approval from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to introduce ethereum futures to its existing Bitcoin futures ETF, creating the Valkyrie Bitcoin and Ether Strategy ETF available from Monday. This is the first time investors can access Ethereum-based futures via an ETF, marking a significant milestone for the cryptocurrency market. Rival firms VanEck and ProShares have also been authorized to launch similar offerings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] MIT researchers analyze Alzheimer&amp;#39;s brains, identify genetic and molecular foundations. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://neurosciencenews.com/alzhiemers-genetics-23991/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Neuroscience News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;MIT researchers have conducted the most comprehensive study yet on Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease, examining over 2 million brain cells from 400 deceased patients. Their findings suggest that Alzheimer&amp;#39;s is not just influenced by one factor but is a complex interplay of genetic and lifestyle changes. In addition to discovering that certain brain cells known as &amp;quot;inhibitory neurons&amp;quot; could be crucial in resisting the disease, they also found that immune cells in the brain, called microglia, exacerbate the condition by adopting inflammatory states. Moreover, as neurons age, their ability to repair DNA diminishes, further accelerating the disease. The team is exploring AI technologies to find new treatments based on these insights, offering a fresh approach to combatting Alzheimer&amp;#39;s beyond the traditional focus on brain plaques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=d50fc728-076a-4fb5-adb7-c6af457680bd&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 28 日，星期四 — 主要更新和 2 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>与中国有关的网络威胁；纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫大规模逃亡</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-september-28-major-update-and-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/thursday-september-28-major-update-and-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 15:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-28T15:23:47Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Hey everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I have a big and exciting update to share. It’s longer than usual, so I put it after the news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1190 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 2 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/78ef8b3a-8a9e-4661-ba5f-792ec1e99066/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.7] U.S. and Japanese agencies warn companies about China-linked hacker group BlackTech. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-japan-authorities-warn-china-linked-hacking-group-blacktech-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The U.S. National Security Agency, Federal Bureau of Investigation, and Japanese police have issued a joint advisory warning multinational companies about the China-linked hacker group BlackTech. The advisory urged companies to review their internet routers to minimize the risk of potential attacks from the group, which has been engaging in cyberattacks on governments and tech-sector companies since around 2010. The advisory comes amid heightened tensions between the U.S. and China over cybersecurity issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Mass exodus of ethnic Armenians from Nagorno-Karabakh after Azerbaijan takeover. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/more-than-half-armenians-nagorno-karabakh-have-left-2023-09-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;More than half of the 120,000 ethnic Armenians in Nagorno-Karabakh have fled the region in less than four days after Azerbaijan took control, marking an unprecedented exodus in the South Caucasus. Azerbaijan has stated that it will respect ethnic Armenian rights, but due to historical tensions and fears of genocide and ethnic cleansing, many Armenians are leaving in fear. As of Thursday morning, over 65,000 people had crossed into neighboring Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Now, the update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adding live coverage and solving topic fatigue.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Three problems bugged News Minimalist website from the start: stale news, bad updates timing, and repetitive content. And I think I finally solved them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Problems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Since the very beginning of the project, the news was grouped by days. The algorithm collected news for 24 hours, rated all articles, and showed the results for the next 24 hours. The system was built around this newsletter that was sent daily. But it had three major problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;First, the news was becoming stale. Since the website was static for 24 hours, it considerably lagged behind the events by the end of that window. The problem was even worse than it appeared: since the website didn&amp;#39;t change for 24 hours after the update, in the worst-case scenario you could read news with a 48-hour delay!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Second, the website was updated too late for many parts of the world. If you&amp;#39;re in the Americas, the website was updated from 5 to 9 a.m. based on your timezone, letting you read fresh news in the morning. But for other parts of the world, the update came too late: around lunch for Europe and dinner in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The third problem was that deduplication only worked on news within 24 hours. The next day, the deduplication algorithm analyzed the entirely new batch of articles with no overlap. That led to people seeing news about the same event every day, leading to &amp;quot;topic fatigue&amp;quot; — where a single event is covered so much that it&amp;#39;s not interesting anymore and causes frustration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 class="heading" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Solution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The first part of the solution is simple: News Minimalist switches to live coverage. Now the website is updated every hour, letting people learn about new events almost in real-time and when they find it convenient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;But the second part took me a long time to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;The deduplication algorithm now works continuously, analyzing a sliding 72-hour window of articles instead of 24-hour non-overlapping batches. This extends the purpose of the algorithm: from finding plain duplicates, to organizing articles into &amp;quot;stories&amp;quot; covering one event. Now, the crucial part here is that stories are sorted by their start time: new stories at the top, and older at the bottom. Once the oldest article in a story falls out of the 72-hour window, it gets replaced by a slightly newer but still old article, keeping the story at the bottom. This should solve the issue of &amp;quot;topic fatigue&amp;quot; — something entirely new and unexpected must happen for an article to break away from the story and form a new story that would appear at the top. The older story will still be available at the bottom and will continue to give ongoing coverage of the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;This is still a bit raw. I will be adjusting the length of the window and the “closeness” of articles in one story over the next several weeks to improve the feed even more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;I am very excited to share this — this is a new chapter for News Minimalist and I hope you’ll like it: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;https://www.newsminimalist.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thank you all,&lt;br&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=68490037-9f73-4ee8-95cd-64b1fdd7f183&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 27 日星期三——5 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>FTC 起诉亚马逊、欧盟对马斯克的警告、中国的应用商店法规、FCC 的网络中立复兴、久坐的生活方式风险</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-27-5-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-27-5-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 13:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-27T13:46:37Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1226 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 5 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/eb3a4778-9cff-4b83-8996-77adc672acb0/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.6] FTC files antitrust lawsuit against Amazon, alleging harm to consumers. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-sues-amazoncom-breaking-antitrust-law-harming-consumers-2023-09-26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has filed an antitrust lawsuit against Amazon, following a long-standing accusation of the company misusing its monopoly power and forcing sellers to use its services, thereby increasing costs. The lawsuit, supported by 17 state attorneys general, could potentially force Amazon to sell assets to restore fair competition. Amazon refutes these claims, suggesting that their practices spur innovation and competition within the retail industry, benefitting consumers and businesses. Amazon&amp;#39;s shares fell 4% after the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] EU warns Elon Musk to comply with new laws on fake news and Russian propaganda. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/26/eu-warns-elon-musk-that-twitter-x-must-comply-with-fake-news-laws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The EU has warned Elon Musk to comply with new laws on fake news and Russian propaganda after X (formerly known as Twitter) was found to have the highest ratio of disinformation posts among large social media platforms. Facebook was the second worst offender, according to a report on posts that will be deemed illegal under the Digital Services Act. While Facebook, Google, TikTok, and Microsoft have signed up to the EU&amp;#39;s code of practice, Twitter is obliged to comply with the new laws or face a ban across the EU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] China enforces new rules on mobile app stores, Apple excluded. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-enforces-new-filing-rules-smartphone-app-stores-2023-09-27/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;China&amp;#39;s cyberspace regulator has started enforcing new rules overseeing mobile apps, with 26 app stores, including those operated by Tencent, Huawei, and Samsung, submitting business details. However, Apple&amp;#39;s App Store is noticeably absent from the list. The heightened scrutiny, a part of Beijing&amp;#39;s expanding oversight of smartphone usage, mandates app stores and apps to report business details to the government, intensifying concerns about app publishing and availability in the country. Compliance could significantly impact the availability of apps in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Sitting for long hours increases dementia risk, exercise doesn&amp;#39;t help. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2023/09/27/sitting-sedentary-exercise-dementia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A recent study published in JAMA has revealed that prolonged sitting can significantly increase the risk of developing dementia, impacting even those who maintain regular exercise routines. The study, examining nearly 50,000 men and women aged 60 or above, found a strong correlation between sedentary behavior and the onset of dementia within seven years. Individuals seated for at least 10 hours daily had an 8% higher risk, escalating to 63% for those seated 12 hours or more. Contrarily, people sedentary for under 9.5 hours didn’t show any increased risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] FCC to reinstate net neutrality rules for equal internet treatment. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/09/26/fcc-announces-plans-to-reinstate-net-neutrality/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The FCC, led by Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, is working to reinstate net neutrality, requiring broadband providers to treat all internet traffic equally. This move would prevent providers from favoring their own services or those of business partners. Net neutrality had been overturned during the previous administration but is deemed essential for fair access to online resources. The renewed rules aim to classify broadband as a necessity, like water and power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=03214b59-8520-413c-a3cb-7b40d9a66823&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 26 日星期二——6 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>南极冰危机、Covid药物突变风险、“皮罗拉”变种、全球贸易衰退、错误信息政策转变、增强的ChatGPT</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-26-6-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-26-6-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-26T14:16:16Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1213 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 6 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/33ee04d5-a928-4f4c-8ced-d276e2b66980/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.9] Antarctic sea ice hits record low, raising climate change concerns. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/antarctic-winter-sea-ice-hits-record-low-sparking-climate-worries-2023-09-25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Antarctic sea ice reached record low levels this winter, according to the U.S. National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC), raising concerns about the impact of climate change on the region. The extent of sea ice peaked on September 10 at 16.96 million square kilometers, the lowest winter maximum since satellite records began in 1979. This is about 1 million square kilometers less than the previous winter record set in 1986. The reduction in sea ice can have negative consequences for animals like penguins and can also contribute to global warming by reducing the amount of sunlight reflected back into space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] COVID-19 drug molnupiravir may cause harmful virus mutations. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://thehill.com/policy/healthcare/4222003-potential-link-found-between-merck-antiviral-and-mutated-covid-strains/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A study published in the Nature science journal suggests that the COVID-19 antiviral drug molnupiravir, developed by Merck, may be linked to the emergence of new mutations of the virus. The researchers found that the drug induces high rates of mutations in the virus, with a &amp;quot;high proportion&amp;quot; of these mutations likely to be harmful to the virus. They also found that many of the mutations observed in sequenced COVID-19 genomes in 2022 were consistent with mutations found in patients treated with molnupiravir.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] New Covid variant &amp;quot;Pirola&amp;quot; with 30+ spike protein mutations detected. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/pirola-variant-symptoms-covid-b2418666.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A new Covid variant called &amp;quot;Pirola&amp;quot; is spreading in the United States and has more than 30 mutations to its spike protein compared to the XBB.1.5 variant of Omicron, according to Yale Medicine. The variant has been found in 10 states and has also been detected in several other countries. Experts are closely monitoring the variant and its potential impact on transmission and immunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Global trade volumes decline due to rising interest rates and inflation. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/36982601-b799-4166-9e6b-39533efbdfdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Global trade volumes fell at their fastest annual pace in almost three years in July, with a 3.2% decrease compared to the same month last year, according to the Netherlands Bureau for Economic Policy Analysis. The decline in trade volumes is seen as a result of rising interest rates impacting global demand for goods, as well as higher inflation and reduced spending on global goods exports. The figures suggest that global growth is slowing and sentiment indicators indicate that world trade will remain weak in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] Tech platforms backtrack on misinformation policies, raising concerns for elections. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.straitstimes.com/world/united-states/us-tech-firms-roll-back-misinformation-curbs-ahead-of-2024-polls" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Tech platforms like YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter are rolling back policies aimed at curbing misinformation and falsehoods ahead of the upcoming global election season, raising concerns about their ability to tackle the expected deluge of misinformation during over 50 major elections next year. These changes come amidst layoffs, cost-cutting measures, and pressure from right-wing groups accusing the platforms of suppressing free speech. Critics argue that these moves have left democracies vulnerable to election interference, hate speech, and violent coup attempts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] ChatGPT gets voice and image support, bringing it closer to AI assistants like Siri. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/25/chatgpt-voice-update-siri-alexa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;OpenAI&amp;#39;s ChatGPT is receiving an update that will allow the chatbot to have voice conversations with users and interact using images, bringing it closer to popular AI assistants like Siri. The voice feature has various applications, including creative and accessibility-focused uses, while the image support enables users to troubleshoot, analyze data, and plan meals. The new features will be rolled out to subscribers of ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Plus and Enterprise plans in the next two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=cc0f18c0-b32e-4dcb-8021-7efb0f85e2dd&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 25 日星期一——3 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>亚马逊的人工智能投资、欧洲的噪音污染、新加坡的二战炸弹</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-25-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-25-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-25T15:08:55Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1146 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/891c78e3-7ed2-4866-b52c-c87772d5b0de/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Amazon invests $4 billion in AI start-up Anthropic. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/25/business/amazon-anthropic-ai-deal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Amazon has announced plans to invest up to $4 billion in AI start-up Anthropic, known as one of the main competitors of OpenAI and operating a chatbot named Claude. Joining other tech giants like Microsoft and Google in the race, Amazon&amp;#39;s investment in Anthropic will leverage its data centers, cloud-computing platform, and AI chips. The investment will give Amazon a minority stake in the start-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] 1 in 5 Europeans exposed to harmful noise levels, health risks. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2023/sep/24/should-i-worry-about-noise-pollution" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;At least one in five Europeans are exposed to noise levels considered harmful to their health, according to the European Environment Agency (EEA), with that number projected to increase. In the UK alone, road, railway, and aircraft noise are estimated to cause over 6,000 new cases of ischaemic heart disease, 1,000 premature deaths, and 750,000 cases of sleep disturbance each year. Chronic noise exposure is also associated with increased risk for hypertension, strokes, and dementia, and noise pollution is a problem that society needs to address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Singapore residents evacuated due to WWII bomb detonation. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/more-than-4k-residents-and-1k-homes-affected-by-upper-bukit-timah-bomb-disposal-operation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;More than 4,000 residents in Singapore will have to evacuate their homes on Tuesday as a World War II era bomb is detonated nearby. The bomb, weighing 100kg, was found at a construction site and is too dangerous to move. This is the largest evacuation exercise involving the detonation of a WWII relic, with over 1,000 homes affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=5b44511b-10ce-42f3-8721-1c1f8faee864&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 24 日，星期日——4 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>iPhone 12 法国禁令、全球降息信号、苹果安全争夺战、中国房地产过剩</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-september-24-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/sunday-september-24-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 13:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-24T13:35:36Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1024 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/65ae387f-5fbe-4b05-8341-fbcb83e7b71c/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.6] iPhone 12 banned in France for exceeding radiation limits. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-iphone-12-isnt-the-only-phone-to-fail-frances-radiation-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;WIRED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The iPhone 12 has been banned in France after failing radiation testing conducted by the Agence Nationale des Fréquences. The testing found that the iPhone 12 emitted radiation levels above the permitted maximum, with a measurement of 5.74 W/kg compared to the limit of 4 W/kg for the 0-mm distance test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Global central banks signal end of interest rate hikes amid economic slowdown. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/18ccb74f-52c1-4d94-a7f1-5541b134d5c0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Central banks around the world are increasingly signaling that the era of interest rate hikes is coming to an end, as evidence of a global economic slowdown mounts. This week, central banks in the US, UK, Japan, and Switzerland all decided to keep rates on hold, with many economists now expecting more rate cuts than hikes in the next quarter. The change in attitude comes as inflation slows in many countries and economic activity weakens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Zero-day attack targets Egyptian politician, prompts Apple security update. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/2023/09/23/predator-egypt-hack-spyware-iphone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Google and the University of Toronto&amp;#39;s Citizen Lab have discovered a previously unknown &amp;quot;zero-day&amp;quot; attack targeting an Egyptian opposition politician, Ahmed Eltantawy, in an attempt to infect his iPhone with Predator spyware. The attack, believed to be orchestrated by the Egyptian government, prompted Apple to release a security update to users. Zero-day exploits are highly valuable as they take advantage of undiscovered security gaps, and the discovery of this exploit prompted Apple to push a security update to users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] China&amp;#39;s property market faces oversupply despite large population. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/even-chinas-14-bln-population-cant-fill-all-its-vacant-homes-former-official-2023-09-23/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;China&amp;#39;s property market continues to struggle, with a former official stating that even the country&amp;#39;s population of 1.4 billion would not be enough to fill all the empty apartments. As of the end of August, the combined floor area of unsold homes stood at 648 million square meters, equivalent to 7.2 million homes. This does not include residential projects that have been sold but not completed or vacant homes purchased by speculators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=4798dd61-2d07-4ee1-a168-07832741d12f&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 23 日星期六——3 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>美国政府关门迫在眉睫，新冠病毒测试计划重启，欧元区经济陷入困境</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-september-23-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/saturday-september-23-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 14:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-23T14:19:50Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1021 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/f3930505-4e5e-424d-bbcc-b581257a83fc/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Possible government shutdown in 8 days; financial hardship, disruptions expected. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2023/09/22/us-braces-calamitous-costly-government-shutdown-eight-days/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The U.S. is approaching a possible government shutdown in 8 days, which means a temporary halt in the funding of non-essential federal programs and services due to a budget disagreement in Congress. If unresolved, 2.2 million federal employees could go unpaid. This could halt services from foreign military aid to domestic infrastructure. About 10,000 children might lose Head Start childcare access, and programs like WIC, which offers nutrition to women and children, face threats. Prolonged inaction could intensify hardships for many families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] The US Department of Health and Human Services restarts mail-order Covid test program. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/how-to-get-free-covid-tests-b2416930.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The US Department of Health and Human Services has announced the restart of its mail-order Covid test program, which was halted in May. The Biden administration has also granted $600m to Covid test manufacturers, securing approximately 200 million new over-the-counter tests for future federal government use. Starting from 25 September, Americans will be able to order free tests from &lt;a class="link" href="http://COVIDTests.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;COVIDTests.gov&lt;/a&gt;, with all households eligible for four tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.0] Eurozone businesses see decline in new orders, raising economic concerns. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ft.com/content/148adc6b-98f3-4655-a92b-913a232c9eef" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Eurozone businesses experienced the largest decline in new orders in almost three years, raising concerns of an economic contraction in the bloc. The flash composite purchasing managers&amp;#39; index (PMI) rose to a two-month high of 47.1 in September, but remained below the 50 mark that separates contraction from expansion, indicating a sharp decline in new orders. The grim economic outlook led investors to believe that the recent interest rate rise by the European Central Bank would be its last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=9a93b98b-a3f0-4040-b4f7-a03447aaf689&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 22 日星期五——3 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>央行与通货膨胀、南美洲的灼热热浪、AlphaFold 的诺贝尔奖潜力</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-22-3-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/friday-september-22-3-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-22T13:48:29Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(34, 34, 34);font-family:Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;font-size:16px;"&gt;(no significant news yesterday)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1226 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 3 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/a55ae930-2644-466b-bc8a-5c694f8e1639/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] Central banks aim to control inflation, but doubts remain. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/global-central-banks-unite-higher-longer-credo-2023-09-21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Central banks, including the U.S. Federal Reserve, European Central Bank, and Bank of England, have pledged to keep interest rates high enough for long enough to tame inflation, as two years of global policy tightening reaches its peak. The goal is to return the global economy to stable prices without a recession, but central banks must convince financial markets not to bet on early rate cuts and watch for new risks such as rising oil prices. Despite the tough rhetoric, investors remain skeptical that central banks will stay the course, with some predicting that 21 out of the world&amp;#39;s 30 major central banks will be cutting interest rates by next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Record-breaking heatwave hits South America, temperatures exceed 110 degrees Fahrenheit. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2023/09/21/extreme-winter-heat-brazil-bolivia-paraguay-south-america/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Parts of Brazil, Paraguay, Argentina, and Bolivia are experiencing record-breaking heat, with temperatures regularly exceeding 110 degrees Fahrenheit (43 degrees Celsius). This heatwave comes after a winter that barely felt like one in several South American countries and is part of what is likely to be the world&amp;#39;s hottest September on record. The heat is being caused by a heat dome of high pressure, boosted by the developing El Niño, and is expected to continue into early next week, with temperatures reaching 110 to 120 degrees Fahrenheit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.9] AlphaFold wins Lasker award for predicting protein structures accurately. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/sep/21/team-behind-ai-program-alphafold-win-lasker-science-prize" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Google DeepMind&amp;#39;s AlphaFold program, developed by Demis Hassabis and John Jumper, has won the $250,000 Lasker basic medical research award for its ability to predict the 3D shapes of proteins, a challenge that has stumped scientists for 50 years. The award is significant because many Lasker winners go on to receive the Nobel prize, potentially making AlphaFold the first AI research to earn a Nobel. AlphaFold&amp;#39;s impact on research has been substantial, with its predicted protein structures database turbocharging research across various scientific fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=6f6e57b6-e604-4e8f-b450-511aeea50f43&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 20 日星期三——4 条重要新闻报道</title>
<description>欧洲空气污染危机、美国免费新冠疫苗、也门和平谈判取得进展、主要领导人错过联合国气候峰会</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-20-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/wednesday-september-20-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-20T13:40:27Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1239 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/e1e34bd8-7a70-4e8f-a4d7-6289d086b035/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.8] Europeans exposed to dangerous levels of air pollution, investigation finds. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/sep/20/revealed-almost-everyone-in-europe-breathing-toxic-air" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;An investigation by The Guardian has found that almost everyone in Europe is living in areas with dangerous levels of air pollution, with 98% of people living in areas with highly damaging fine particulate pollution that exceed World Health Organization guidelines (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2023/sep/20/europes-pollution-divide-see-how-your-area-compares" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Interactive pollution map&lt;/a&gt;). The worst-hit country is North Macedonia, where almost two-thirds of people live in areas with more than four times the WHO guidelines for PM2.5. Eastern Europe is significantly worse than western Europe, apart from Italy, where more than a third of those living in the Po valley and surrounding areas in the north of the country breathe air that is four times the WHO figure for the most dangerous airborne particulates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.7] Uninsured Americans can get free Covid vaccines at select locations. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/09/19/covid-vaccine-boosters-uninsured-americans-can-find-free-moderna-pfizer-shots.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Uninsured Americans can now receive the latest Covid vaccines for free at select locations, following recent approval by U.S. regulators. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommended the updated Pfizer and Moderna vaccines for all Americans 6 months and older. The federal government&amp;#39;s &lt;a class="link" href="http://Vaccines.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Vaccines.gov&lt;/a&gt; website assists patients in locating free vaccination sites, which are part of the Biden administration&amp;#39;s Bridge Access Program. This program aims to offer free Covid vaccines to the uninsured until December 2024, bridging the gap left by shifts in the U.S. distribution approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] Saudi Arabia optimistic about progress in Yemen peace talks. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-arabia-reaffirms-its-commitment-promoting-dialogue-among-all-parties-yemen-2023-09-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Saudi Arabia has expressed optimism about the progress made in discussions with Houthi negotiators to support the peace process in Yemen. The talks, which focused on issues such as the reopening of ports and airports, payment of public wages, and the withdrawal of foreign forces, have shown some progress on key points. The conflict in Yemen, which began in 2014, has resulted in hundreds of thousands of deaths and has left 80% of the population reliant on humanitarian aid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] Leaders of major polluting countries skip UN climate summit. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/20/un-climate-summit-polluting-countries-leaders-skipping" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Leaders of major polluting countries, including the US, China, the UK, and France, are skipping a UN climate summit aimed at addressing the climate crisis. The summit, convened by UN Secretary-General António Guterres, features over 100 national governments outlining plans to curb global heating, but has failed to attract the leaders of the two biggest carbon emitters. The absence of major emitters, along with geopolitical tensions, has overshadowed the summit, which climate advocates hope will include pledges to cut emissions and phase out fossil fuel subsidies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=875ab110-dc8d-4a94-a705-f78907c93766&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 19 日星期二——4 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>锂离子突破、澳大利亚的气候威胁、人工智能诊断多囊卵巢综合症、美国宇航局的太阳遭遇</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-19-4-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/tuesday-september-19-4-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-19T13:40:57Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1268 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 4 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/f5ef14a7-7153-4adf-a028-cbf2d4866df3/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.4] Lithium-ion battery costs drop, accelerating EV transition. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/tech/battery-price-increase-electric-car-lithium-b2414028.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The cost of lithium-ion batteries fell by nearly 10% in August, dropping below $100/kWh, a key milestone that is expected to accelerate the transition to electric vehicles. This represents a 33% drop from March 2022 and an 8.7% month-on-month decrease. The falling prices are attributed to decreasing raw material costs, particularly the halving of lithium prices since the start of 2023, and the discovery of massive lithium deposits, such as the McDermitt caldera, which could potentially meet global battery demand for decades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.3] El Niño and positive Indian Ocean Dipole bring hot, dry conditions to Australia. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-09-19/bom-officially-declares-el-nino-underway-2023/102495394" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;ABC News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Bureau of Meteorology has announced that two major climate drivers associated with hot, dry conditions are active in Australia: the El Niño weather pattern and a &amp;quot;positive&amp;quot; Indian Ocean Dipole, which refers to temperature differences in the Indian Ocean that influence Australia&amp;#39;s climate. This is the first appearance of El Niño in the Pacific in eight years. The convergence of these climate phenomena indicates that Australia, especially its eastern states, is poised for a notably hot and dry remainder of 2023. Coupled with ongoing climate change effects, there are concerns of elevated fire risks and extremely hot days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.2] AI and ML can detect and diagnose PCOS with high accuracy. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nih.gov/news-events/news-releases/ai-machine-learning-can-successfully-diagnose-polycystic-ovary-syndrome" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;National Institutes of Health (.gov)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A study by the National Institutes of Health revealed that AI and machine learning can effectively detect and diagnose Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS), a prevalent hormone disorder among women aged 15 to 45. PCOS can cause symptoms like irregular periods and increased testosterone levels, with associated risks such as type 2 diabetes and uterine cancer. The use of AI can enhance diagnosis accuracy, especially given the overlapping symptoms of PCOS with other conditions. The research highlights the potential for AI in healthcare to improve diagnosis and reduce system burdens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.1] NASA&amp;#39;s Parker Solar Probe survives intense solar explosion during mission. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://mashable.com/article/sun-solar-ejection-nasa-footage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;A NASA spacecraft, the Parker Solar Probe, recently flew through a powerful coronal mass ejection (CME) from the sun, one of the most intense ever recorded. Captured in footage released by the Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory, the probe spent around two days observing this massive solar explosion. Scientists are using data from the Parker Solar Probe to understand potentially harmful space weather, such as CMEs which can disrupt technologies on Earth. The probe&amp;#39;s ongoing mission will bring it closer to the sun in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=2ee28a71-32a8-48b7-8eee-32a33311a26e&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>9 月 18 日星期一——2 条重大新闻报道</title>
<description>德尔纳洪水造成毁灭性损失，欧盟迫在眉睫的电池依赖</description>
<link>https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-18-2-significant-news-stories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.newsminimalist.com/p/monday-september-18-2-significant-news-stories</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 13:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
<atom:published>2023-09-18T13:06:44Z</atom:published>
<content:encoded>
    &lt;div class='beehiiv'&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__body'&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Today ChatGPT read 1249 top news stories. After removing previously covered events, there are 2 articles with a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;significance score&lt;/a&gt; over 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="image__image" src="https://media.beehiiv.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=scale-down,format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=80/uploads/asset/file/e27127b0-d000-47c3-8ce3-7060e9a453bb/image.png"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.6] Severe flooding in Derna, Libya leaves thousands dead and displaced. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/libyan-flood-survivors-weigh-water-shortages-against-landmine-risk-2023-09-17/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Severe flooding in Derna, Libya resulted from the breaking of two dams on September 10, leading to massive devastation in the region. The United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs reported a death toll of 11,300, although the exact number remains disputed. The flooding displaced more than 40,000 individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;[7.5] EU&amp;#39;s lithium-ion battery dependency on China could mirror energy dependency on Russia. — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/eu-may-become-hooked-china-batteries-it-was-russian-energy-paper-2023-09-17/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"&gt;The European Union could become as dependent on China for lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells by 2030 as it was on Russia for energy before the war in Ukraine, according to a paper prepared for EU leaders. The paper highlights the need for the EU to take strong measures to reduce its dependency on China and diversify towards Africa and Latin America, as the demand for lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells is expected to multiply between 10 and 30 times in the coming years due to the need for energy storage to reach the EU&amp;#39;s goal of net-zero carbon dioxide emissions by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Want to read more?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;See additional news on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsminimalist.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;newsminimalist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="content_break"&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Thanks for reading us and see you tomorrow,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph" style="text-align:start;"&gt;Vadim&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='beehiiv__footer'&gt;&lt;br class='beehiiv__footer__break'&gt;&lt;hr class='beehiiv__footer__line'&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="beehiiv__footer_link" style="text-align: center;" href="https://www.beehiiv.com/?utm_campaign=d470aa22-678f-42c1-bfaa-e35c897d2af3&amp;amp;utm_medium=post_rss&amp;amp;utm_source=news_minimalist_daily"&gt;Powered by beehiiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  </content:encoded>
</item>









</channel>
</rss>